<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Abate</title>
 <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/"/>
 <updated>2023-03-17T22:56:08-07:00</updated>
 <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website</id>
 <author>
   <name>Abate De Mey</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Shaking Up The Sheetmetal Industry, with  Ed Mehr</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2023/02/17/ep.364-Shaking-Up-The-Sheetmetal-Industry,-with-Ed-Mehr/"/>
   <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2023/02/17/ep.364:-Shaking-Up-The-Sheetmetal-Industry,-with--Ed-Mehr</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Machina-Logo-Forming-1024x668.jpeg &quot; alt=&quot;robohub cover image&quot; /&gt;
Conventional sheet metal manufacturing is highly inefficient for the low-volume production seen in the space industry. At Machina Labs, they developed a novel method of forming sheet metal using two robotic arms to bend the metal into different geometries. This method cuts down the time to produce large sheet metal parts from several months down to a few hours. Ed Mehr, Co-Founder and CEO of Machina Labs, explains this revolutionary manufacturing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ULrld1ti-0I&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ed Mehr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed Mehr is the co-founder and CEO of Machina Labs. He has an engineering background in smart manufacturing and artificial intelligence. In his previous position at Relativity Space, he led a team in charge of developing the world’s largest metal 3D printer. Relativity Space uses 3D printing to make rocket parts rapidly, and with the flexibility for multiple iterations. Ed previously was the CTO at Cloudwear (Now Averon), and has also worked at SpaceX, Google, and Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Going out on a Bionic Limb, with  Joel Gibbard</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/12/21/ep.363-Going-out-on-a-Bionic-Limb-with-Joel-Gibbard/"/>
   <updated>2022-12-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/12/21/ep.363-Going-out-on-a-Bionic-Limb-with-Joel-Gibbard</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/openbionics2-1024x968.jpeg &quot; alt=&quot;robohub cover image&quot; /&gt;
Joel Gibbard, co-founder of Open Bionics dives deep into their creative, imagination-capturing prosthetic limbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UyIcwNjZWJU&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Recycling</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/10/10/ep.361-Recycling-An-Opaque-Industry-with-Areeb-Malik/"/>
   <updated>2022-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/10/10/ep.361-Recycling-An-Opaque-Industry-with-Areeb-Malik</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/glacier_robot-1024x715.jpeg &quot; alt=&quot;robohub cover image&quot; /&gt;
Areeb, the co-founder of Glacier, gives some insight into the opaque recycling industry, and why it is unable to handle the volume of recyclable good Americans through out each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/389pabvhve4&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Building Communities Around AI in Africa, with  Benjamin Rosman</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/09/14/ep.360-Building-Communities-Around-AI-in-Africa-with-Benjamin-Rosman/"/>
   <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/09/14/ep.360-Building-Communities-Around-AI-in-Africa-with-Benjamin-Rosman</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/crowd-1920x1188-1-1024x634.jpeg &quot; alt=&quot;robohub cover image&quot; /&gt;
Deep Learning Indaba is an organization that empowers and builds communities around Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning across Africa. Benjamin Rosman dives into how Deep Learning Indaba is impacting these communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JyH8duuxchc&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Softbank</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/08/03/ep.358-Softbank-How-Large-Companies-Approach-Robotics-with-Brady-Watkins/"/>
   <updated>2022-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/08/03/ep.358-Softbank-How-Large-Companies-Approach-Robotics-with-Brady-Watkins</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/softbank_robots-1024x527.png &quot; alt=&quot;robohub cover image&quot; /&gt;
Brady Watkins gives insights into how a large company like Softbank Robotics approaches the Robotics market&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Origin Story of the OAK-D, with  Brandon Gilles</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/07/01/ep.357-Origin-Story-of-the-OAK-D-with-Brandon-Gilles/"/>
   <updated>2022-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/07/01/ep.357-Origin-Story-of-the-OAK-D-with-Brandon-Gilles</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Screen-Shot-2022-06-29-at-12.34.50-AM-1024x564.png &quot; alt=&quot;robohub cover image&quot; /&gt;
Brandon Gilles, the founder of Luxonis and maker of the OAK-D, describes the journey and the flexibility of the OAK-D line of products&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_nH_s7KIkkM&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Autonomous Need for Speed, with  Joe Speed</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/04/08/ep.349-Autonomous-Need-for-Speed-with-Joe-Speed/"/>
   <updated>2022-04-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/04/08/ep.349-Autonomous-Need-for-Speed-with-Joe-Speed</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ApexAi_cover_photo-1024x577.jpg &quot; alt=&quot;robohub cover image&quot; /&gt;
Joe Speed, VP of Product at ApexAI, dives into the current multi-year development process of bringing a car to market, and how ApexAI will transform this process into the shorter development time we see with modern technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OldxjlzyyOk&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Event Cameras – An Evolution in Visual Data Capture, with  Davide Scaramuzza</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/03/08/ep.347-Event-Cameras-An-Evolution-in-Visual-Data-Capture-with-Davide-Scaramuzza/"/>
   <updated>2022-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2022/03/08/ep.347-Event-Cameras-–-An-Evolution-in-Visual-Data-Capture-with-Davide-Scaramuzza</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/davide-scaramuzza-1024x703.jpg &quot; alt=&quot;robohub cover image&quot; /&gt;
Davide Scaramuzza deep dives into Event Cameras, a fundamentally new approach to capturing visual data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-Tthu0D4dps&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Autonomous Aircraft, with Xwing</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2021/07/12/autonomous-aircraft-xwing/"/>
   <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2021/07/12/autonomous-aircraft-xwing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/xwing_Aircraft.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;xwing autonomous aircraft&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to Maxime Gariel, CTO of Xwing about the autonomous flight technology they are developing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Xwing, they are converting traditional aircraft into remotely operated aircraft. They do this by retrofitting planes with multiple sensors including cameras, radar, and lidar, and by developing sensor fusion algorithms to allow their planes to understand the world around them, using highly accurate perception algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xwing’s autonomous flight technology allows a plane to taxi in the airport, takeoff, fly to a destination, avoid airborne and ground threats, and land, all without any human input. This technology not only enables autonomous flight but may also enhance the safety of manned aircraft by improving a plane’s ability to understand its surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yb-zwh1SpHQ&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique challenges of operating in autonomously in the air piqued my interest. Unlike with self driving cars, when you are in the sky there are no features you can use to estimate depth and scale using video from a single camera. With objects flying towards you at hundreds of miles an hour, you need to be able to make those measurements rapidly. To solve this, they developed a sensor fusion package that combines video, radar, and ADS-B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maxime Gariel&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/image003-1-290x290.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;290&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maxime Gariel is the CTO of Xwing, a San Francisco based startup whose mission is to dramatically increase human mobility using fully autonomous aerial vehicles. Xwing is developing a Detect-And-Avoid system for unmanned and remotely piloted vehicles. Maxime is a pilot but he is passionate about making airplanes fly themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maxime joined Xwing from Rockwell Collins where he was a Principal GNC Engineer. He worked on autonomous aircraft projects including DARPA Gremlins and the AgustaWestland SW4 Solo autonomous helicopter. Before becoming Chief Engineer of the SW4 Solo’s flight control system, he was in charge of the system architecture, redundancy, and safety for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Rockwell Collins, he worked on ADS-B based conflict detection as a postdoc at MIT and on autoland systems for airliners at Thales. Maxime earned his MS and PhD in Aerospace Engineering from Georgia Tech and his BS from ISAE-Supaéro (France).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CV and ML at the edge, with Intel RealSense</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2021/06/10/intel-realsense/"/>
   <updated>2021-06-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2021/06/10/intel-realsense</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Intel-RealSense-ID-2-scaled-1-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Intel RealSense Facial Scanning&quot; class=&quot;size-large&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intel RealSense is known in the robotics community for its plug-and-play stereo cameras. These cameras make gathering 3D depth data a seamless process, with easy integrations into ROS to simplify the software development for your robots. From the RealSense team, Joel Hagberg talks about how they built this product, which allows roboticists to perform computer vision and machine learning at the edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GsDiqkz3_-8&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through Fluid Design Consultancy, we have come into contact with the RealSense line of products extensively. The ability to add an off the shelf component to instantly give us depth data is a win by itself. The ability to leverage an active, open source community that develops software packages on top of this to extract more value out of the product is magical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joel Hagberg&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Joel_Hagberg_Headshot_16A3639_SQ_Hi_Res-1-290x290.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joel Hagberg leads the Intel® RealSense™ Marketing. Product Management and Customer Support teams.  He joined Intel in 2018 after a few years as an Executive Advisor working with startups in the IoT, AI, Flash Array, and SaaS markets.  Before his Executive Advisor role, Joel spent two years as Vice President of Product Line Management at Seagate Technology with responsibility for their $13B product portfolio.  He joined Seagate from Toshiba, where Joel spent 4 years as Vice President of Marketing and Product Management for Toshiba’s HDD and SSD product lines.  Joel joined Toshiba with Fujitsu’s Storage Business acquisition, where Joel spent 12 years as Vice President of Marketing, Product Management, and Business Development.  Joel’s Business Development efforts at Fujitsu focused on building emerging market business units in Security, Biometric Sensors, H.264 HD Video Encoders, 10GbE chips, and Digital Signage.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Construction Site Automation, with Dusty Robotics</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2021/03/12/construction-site-automation/"/>
   <updated>2021-03-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2021/03/12/construction-site-automation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/FieldPrinter-outside_2000x1500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FieldPrinter by Dusty Robotics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to Tessa Lau on her startup Dusty Robotics which is innovating in the field of construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Dusty Robotics, they developed a robot to automate the laying of floor plans on the floors in construction sites. Typically, this is done manually using a tape measure and reading printed out plans. This difficult task can often take a team of two a week to complete. Time-consuming tasks like this are incredibly expensive on a construction site where multiple different teams are waiting on this task to complete. Any errors in this process are even more time-consuming to fix. By using a robot to automatically convert 3d models of building plans into markings on the floors, the amount of time and errors are dramatically reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YaU-oIb_R0o&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out to Tessa originally because I loved their story for how they came up with this concept. By having her own house remodeled, Tessa had to interact with people in the construction industry on a personal level for the first time. In this process, she saw the multitude of subcontractors come in and out of her house and manually doing a multitude of things. Construction is an ever evolving, but incredibly anciant industry. Tessa knew there was room for optimization, but as an outsider she had to be careful and interview a multitude of experts in the field before offering a product in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually she chose to optimize the process of converting floorplans drawn on paper, to physically drawing them out on the floor. A time consuming task for a person that will always lead to cutting corners to get it done in the fastest, simplest way on a construction site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By developing a robot to do this, she was able to add far more information to the floors, and far more accurately than a person would. This presents a step change in quality that makes the product something a construction manager would accept. The fact that this job is not tied to any one person, except likely the construction manager, means that buying this robot is not taking away anyones job, but instead adding value and saving critical time at a construciton site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Tessa Lau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tlau21-290x290.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Tessa Lau is an experienced entrepreneur with expertise in AI, machine learning, and robotics. She is currently Founder/CEO at Dusty Robotics, a construction robotics company building robot-powered tools for the modern construction workforce. Prior to Dusty, she was CTO/co-founder at Savioke, where she orchestrated the deployment of 75+ delivery robots into hotels and high-rises. Previously, Dr. Lau was a Research Scientist at Willow Garage, where she developed simple interfaces for personal robots. She also spent 11 years at IBM Research working in business process automation and knowledge capture. More generally, Dr. Lau is interested in technology that gives people super-powers, and building businesses that bring that technology into people’s lives. Dr. Lau was recognized as one of the Top 5 Innovative Women to Watch in Robotics by Inc. in 2018 and one of Fast Company’s Most Creative People in 2015. Dr. Lau holds a PhD in Computer Science from the University of Washington.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Deep Sea Mining, with Pliant Energy Systems</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2021/01/18/deep-sea-mining/"/>
   <updated>2021-01-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2021/01/18/deep-sea-mining</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pliant_Energy_Systems_blue_swarm_Filardo.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed up with Benjamin Pietro Filardo, founder of Pliant Energy Systems and NACROM, the North American Consortium for Responsible Ocean Mining. Pietro talks about the deep sea mining industry, an untapped market with a massive potential for growth. Pietro discusses the current proposed solutions for deep sea mining which are environmentally destructive, and he offers an alternative solution using swarm robots which could mine the depths of the ocean while creating minimal disturbance to this mysterious habitat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/967923577&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast&quot; title=&quot;Robohub Podcast&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Robohub Podcast&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast/deep-sea-mining&quot; title=&quot;Deep Sea Mining&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Deep Sea Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What made me gravitate to doing a second interview with Pietro is that while talking to him about applications for his robot, I learned a lot about the potential for deep sea mining. The incredible amount of resources laying openly on the seafloor can fuel the battery powered selfless car revolution that is happening on the surface of the Earth. What is stopping us today is how extremely inaccesible this environment is to any type of operations, especially manned vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an industry that will open up around deep sea mining. It is not a question of “if”, but “when” technology can advance enough to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Advantage of Fins, with Pliant Energy Systems</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2020/12/16/the-advantage-of-fins/"/>
   <updated>2020-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2020/12/16/the-advantage-of-fins</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #321: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/empowering-farmers-through-rootai/&quot;&gt;Empowering Farmers through Root AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Pliant_Energy_Velox_beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benjamin “Pietro” Filardo, CEO and founder of Pliant Energy Systems talks about the novel novel form of actuation they developed using two undulating fins on a robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These fins present multiple benefits over traditional propeller systems including excellent energy efficiency, low water turbulence, and an ability to maneuver in water, land, and ice. Aside from its benefits on a robot, Pietro also talks about its advantages for harnessing energy from moving water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/948953797&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast&quot; title=&quot;Robohub Podcast&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Robohub Podcast&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast/the-advantage-of-fins&quot; title=&quot;The Advantage of Fins&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Advantage of Fins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I loved about this interview is how this product completes a full energy cycle. Not only is it able to move around in a low energy way, it is also able to generate its own energy. This paves the way for the robot to stay underwater indefinitely and sustainably, similar to aquatic creatures in the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other aspect that struck me is its ability to operate in what could be considered a niche environment - the coastal waters between land and sea. I say it could be considered niche because it covers only a small portion of the earths surface, but if you consider how the majority of the worlds population is located next to a shoreline, this presents a massive part of how we interact with large bodies of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benjamin “Pietro” Filardo&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pietro_filardo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several years in the architectural profession, Pietro founded Pliant Energy Systems to explore renewable energy concepts he first pondered while earning his first degree in marine biology and oceanography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With funding from four federal agencies he has broadened the application of these concepts into marine propulsion and a highly novel robotics platform.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Empowering Farmers through Root AI</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2020/10/16/empowering-farmers-through-root-ai/"/>
   <updated>2020-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2020/10/16/empowering-farmers-through-root-ai</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #321: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/empowering-farmers-through-rootai/&quot;&gt;Empowering Farmers through Root AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/root_ai.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/913097575&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast&quot; title=&quot;Robohub Podcast&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Robohub Podcast&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast/empowering-farmers-through-rootai&quot; title=&quot;Empowering Farmers Through Root AI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Empowering Farmers Through Root AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh Lessing, co-founder and CEO of Root AI, discusses a system they are developing that tracks data on the farm and autonomously harvests crops using delicate grippers and computer vision. Lessing talks about the path they took to build a product with good market fit and how they brought a venture capital backed startup to market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Josh Lessing&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Josh_Lessing_200pix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; /&gt;
Josh is one of the world’s leading minds on developing robotics and AI systems for the food industry, previously serving as the Director of R&amp;amp;D at Soft Robotics Inc. His current venture, Root AI, is integrating advanced robotics, vision systems and machine perception to automate agriculture. Josh was a Postdoctoral Fellow in Materials Science &amp;amp; Robotics at Harvard University, having earned his Ph.D. studying Biophysics &amp;amp; Physical Chemistry at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and received an Sc.B. in Chemistry from Brown University.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Solid State Lidar - the 3D Camera</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2020/06/29/solid-state-lidar/"/>
   <updated>2020-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2020/06/29/solid-state-lidar</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #313: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/solid-state-lidar-the-3d-camera/&quot;&gt;Solid State Lidar - the 3D Camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/point-cloud-building.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sense Photonics&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/848691523&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast&quot; title=&quot;Robohub Podcast&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Robohub Podcast&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast/solid-state-lidar-the-3d-camera&quot; title=&quot;Solid State Lidar - The 3D Camera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Solid State Lidar - The 3D Camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erin Bishop from Sense Photonics talks about the technology in their “Solid State” LiDAR sensors that allows them to detect objects more accurately and over a larger field of view than traditional scanning LiDAR. Erin dives into the technical details of Solid State Lidar, discusses the applications and industries of the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Erin Bishop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/rapacki-headshot-portrait-resized.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Erin operates at the intersection of product management, project engineering, customer development, and product-market fit within 3D camera company Sense Photonics. Over the past several years, she has worked to initiate the market appetite for telepresence robots, indoor mobile robots, and robotic picking in warehouses. Erin has made appearances at CES, UX Week, RoboBusiness, HardwareCon, and Mobile Future Forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erin creates partnerships that result in large-scale deployment of the company’s revolutionary solid-state FLASH architecture. Prior to joining Sense, she held product manager, marketing, and research roles with several robotics companies, including Industrial Perception, Inc. – which was acquired by Google in 2013 – Adept Technology, iRobot, and DEKA. Erin earned her Master’s in Mechanical Engineering from UMass Lowell, where she performed extensive research in Human-Robot Interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Navigating with Microlocation</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2020/03/06/Microlocation/"/>
   <updated>2020-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2020/03/06/Microlocation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #306: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/microlocation/&quot;&gt;Navigating with Microlocation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Humatics-microlocation.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/784992817&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Mindell, co-founder of Humatics, discusses a system they developed that can detect the location of a special tracking device down to a centimeter level accuracy. They are currently developing a device to detect location down to a millimeter level accuracy. This solves a core problem of localization for robots. David discusses the technology behind these products and their applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;David Mindell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/david-mindell.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
David co-founded Humatics with a mission to revolutionize how people and machines locate, navigate and collaborate. He is a professor of Aeronautics and Astronautics at MIT, as well as the Dibner Professor of the History of Engineering and Manufacturing, and Chair of the MIT Task Force on the Work of the Future. He has participated in more than 25 oceanographic expeditions and is an inventor on 8 patents in autonomous helicopters, AI-assisted piloting, and RF navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Demand Drone Deliveries</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2019/03/05/On-Demand-Drone-Delivery/"/>
   <updated>2019-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2019/03/05/On-Demand-Drone-Delivery</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #281: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/on-demand-drone-deliveries/&quot;&gt;On Demand Drone Deliveries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/flytrex-drone-delivery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-116848&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/585165192&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yariv Bash, CEO of Flytrex, discusses how Flytrex works in cooperation with local businesses in a city to use drones to rapidly transport goods in a local region. A practical application is the delivery of food from local restaurants. Yariv discusses Flytrex’s plans for using their USD$7.5 million series B round of funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Yariv Bash&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-116849 alignleft&quot; src=&quot;/assets/yariv-bash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yariv Bash is the CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flytrex.com/&quot;&gt;Flytrex&lt;/a&gt;, a drone technology company providing comprehensive, autonomous drone delivery systems that enable any business, from SMBs to e-commerce giants, to integrate instant, autonomous on-demand drone delivery into their offering. Flytrex is an end-to-end drone logistics service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nIKSqPKBDYU&quot;&gt;Flytrex 2018 Recap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ixP6zOLu3Gs&quot;&gt;Flytrex Launches Drone Delivery in Reykjavík, Iceland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cozmo, by Anki</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2018/05/29/cozmo-anki/"/>
   <updated>2018-05-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2018/05/29/cozmo-anki</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #220: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/cozmo-by-anki/&quot;&gt;Cozmo, by Anki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignncenter&quot; src=&quot;/assets/cozmo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/450614919&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I interview Andrew Neil Stein from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anki.com/en-us&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt; about their engaging robot, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anki.com/en-us/cozmo&quot;&gt;Cozmo&lt;/a&gt;. Cozmo is a lifelike, palm sized robot that recognizes people and objects around him and plays games with them. Cozmo is unique in that a large amount of development has been implemented to make his animations and behavior feel natural, in addition to focusing on classical robotic elements such as computer vision and object manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Andrew Neil Stein&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/andrew-neil-stein.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewneilstein/&quot;&gt;Andrew Neil Stein&lt;/a&gt; is the Head of Robotics &amp;amp; AI at Anki, where he began working on the Cozmo project more than four years ago as the team’s first member. He has contributed to several core systems of the product, including vision, cube manipulation, animation streaming, localization, high-level behaviors, and low-level actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Collaborative Systems for Drug Discovery</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2018/02/18/collaborative-systems-for-drug-discovery/"/>
   <updated>2018-02-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2018/02/18/collaborative-systems-for-drug-discovery</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #220: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/collaborative-systems-for-drug-discovery/&quot;&gt;Collaborative Systems for Drug Discovery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-97417&quot; src=&quot;/assets/highres-biosolutions.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/401320575&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I interview Peter Harris from HighRes Biosolutions about &lt;a href=&quot;https://content.yudu.com/web/fiqy/0A42big/drugdiscoveryfall17/html/index.html?page=64&amp;amp;origin=reader&quot;&gt;automation in the field of drug discovery&lt;/a&gt;. At HighRes Biosolutions they are developing modular robotic systems that work alongside scientists to automate laboratory tasks. Because the requirements of each biomedical research laboratory are so varied, the robotic systems are specifically tailored to meet the requirements of each lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Peter Harris&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/peter-harris.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Harris is the CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://highresbio.com/&quot;&gt;HighRes Biosolutions&lt;/a&gt;. Prior to HighRes, Peter was VP and Managing Director at Axel Johnson, Inc. He spent most his career as the President &amp;amp; CEO of Cadence, Inc., a medical device manufacturing and engineering firm enabling companies to bring devices to market faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Embedded Platform for SLAM</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2018/01/20/embedded-platform-for-slam/"/>
   <updated>2018-01-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2018/01/20/embedded-platform-for-slam</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #220: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/embedded-platform-for-slam/&quot;&gt;Embedded Platform for SLAM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-95833&quot; src=&quot;/assets/perceptin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/386581616&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zhe Zhang from Perceptin discusses the embedded platforms they are building for robots to do Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM) algorithms in real time. Zhe explains the methods they incorporate such as sensor fusion and hardware synchronization to make a highly accurate SLAM platform for IOT, consumer, and automotive grade robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Zhe Zhang&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left; margin-right:30px;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/zhe-zhang.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zhe is the co-founder and CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perceptin.io&quot;&gt;PerceptIn&lt;/a&gt;. Prior to founding PerceptIn, he worked at Magic Leap in Silicon Valley and prior to that he worked for five years at Microsoft. Zhang has a PhD in Robotics from the State University of New York and an undergraduate degree from Tsinghua University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Locus Robotics</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2017/05/28/locus-robotics-rick-faulk/"/>
   <updated>2017-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2017/05/28/locus-robotics-rick-faulk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #235: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/locus-robotics/&quot;&gt;Locus Robotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-77490 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;/assets/locus-robotics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/324943131&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rick Faulk, CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.locusrobotics.com/&quot;&gt;Locus Robotics&lt;/a&gt;, talks with me about warehouse automation with collaborative robots. At Locus Robotics, they increase the productivity of workers in e-commerce warehouses by using robot helpers to transport items that are passed to them by the workers. The lightweight autonomous robots move at a similar pace to their co-workers, use LIDAR and computer vision to detect people and avoid collisions. This allows people to share the warehouse floor with the robots. The collaborative robotic system is lightweight and can be adapted to existing warehouses with minimal alterations. Check out their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rGeu76wXtnk&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>RoboUniverse Conference - Drones, AI, and 3D Printing</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2017/02/19/Robouniverse-conference-Drone-AI-3D-printing/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2017/02/19/Robouniverse-conference-Drone-AI-3D-printing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #220: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/robouniverse-conference-drones-ai-and-3d-printing-part-2-of-2/&quot;&gt;Robouniverse Conference - Drones, AI, and 3D Printing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-72095&quot; src=&quot;/assets/brain-corp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/308447815&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I interview three speakers from the Artificial Intelligence and Drone tracks at RoboUniverse San Diego and the Inside 3D Printing Conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Dr. Douglas Stow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Douglas Stow discusses the &lt;a href=&quot;https://geog.sdsu.edu/Research/Projects/TS_Detection/&quot;&gt;use of drones&lt;/a&gt; in analyzing large scale changes over time in terrains, and its applications in determining the extent of damage after a natural disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Stow is a Professor of Geography at San Diego State University (SDSU) and has been on the faculty for 33 years. He has worked in the remote sensing field for almost 40 years and his research focuses on multitemporal image analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Dr. Eugene Izhikevich&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Eugene Izhikevich discusses how Brain Corporation converts manually driven industrial machines into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-4QkyHapXSA&quot;&gt;autonomous robots&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known for his contributions to the theory of spiking networks, in 2005 Dr. Izhikevich implemented the world’s largest thalamo-cortical model. It simulated one hundred billion neurons and one quadrillion synapses - the same number as the human brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cullen Hilkene&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cullen Hilkene discusses how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L-5NS1bCGZk&quot;&gt;3Diligent&lt;/a&gt; optimizes the work flow and communication layer between a diverse set of 3D print vendors and their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cullen Hilkene is CEO of 3Diligent, “the 3D Printing Partner for Every Business.” 3Diligent is a web-based rapid manufacturing service described as “Uber meets Amazon for 3D Printing, CNC Machining, and Molding and Casting.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>RoboUniverse Conference - Agricultural Robotics</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2017/02/04/RoboUniverse-conference-agricultural-robotics/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2017/02/04/RoboUniverse-conference-agricultural-robotics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #220: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/robouniverse-conference-agricultural-robotics-part-1-of-2/&quot;&gt;Robouniverse Conference - Agricultural Robotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/biotac.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;biotac&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/softrobotics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;softroboticsinc&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/306122533&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I interview two speakers from the Agricultural track of the RoboUniverse 2016 conference in San Diego: Dan Harburg of Soft Robotics Inc. and Matthew Borzage of BioTac. Borzage and Harburg discuss their distinct approaches to advancing gripping technology in Agriculture. Borzage stresses the importance of tactile sensing while Harburg pushes for low cost, soft grippers with no on-board sensors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dan Harburg&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Harburg is the Director of Business Development at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.softroboticsinc.com/&quot;&gt;Soft Robotics Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, a venture-backed startup company developing a soft end-of-arm tool for the food industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Matthew Borzage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Borzage is a co-founder and the Head of Business Development for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.syntouchinc.com/&quot;&gt;SynTouch Inc.&lt;/a&gt;. Borzage has a background in biomedical and medical device engineering and sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o8DoSvv4P3w&quot;&gt;Bakery Automation with a Soft Touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.syntouchinc.com/biomimetic-process/&quot;&gt;Biomimetic Design of BioTac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Actuation for Robotic Fingers</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2016/12/11/actuation-for-robotic-fingers/"/>
   <updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2016/12/11/actuation-for-robotic-fingers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #223: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/actuation-for-robotic-fingers/&quot;&gt;Actuation for Robotic Fingers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;/assets/smac.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/297410127&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I interview Edward Neff, founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smac-mca.com&quot;&gt;SMAC Corporation&lt;/a&gt;. Mr. Neff discusses breakthroughs in his company that allow them to develop linear actuators compact enough to be used to actuate robotic fingers. Companies like Apple and Samsung push for the development of robotic fingers to perform lifelike tests on their phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The robotic fingers developed using SMAC’s linear servo motors simulate a button press on a screen by employing a strong downwards force, as well as small sideways forces tangential to the screen. This mimics a realistic way that people interact with their touchscreens. The robotic fingers can also gently bump into surfaces, pull, and push objects. Other applications for these fingers include electronic circuit board assembly, and screwing bottle caps onto bottles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Videos&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/S8Y0bGsLCvo&quot;&gt;Robotic Finger using a Smart Phone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/G13-5D-C5sM&quot;&gt;Robotic Finger at the Tokyo Robot Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/eZagN2eu164&quot;&gt;Robotic Finger vs Human Finger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/VDQydFc45_o&quot;&gt;Smart Assembly Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Teach Xemo to Move</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2016/10/31/teach-xemo-to-move/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2016/10/31/teach-xemo-to-move</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #220: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/teach-xemo-to-move/&quot;&gt;Teach Xemo to Move&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;/assets/Xemo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/290722073&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode, I interview Jeff Sprenger, founder of the startup Xemory in Vermont, USA. At Xemory they are developing a robot simulation game called Xemo, where players learn to animate virtual robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complex motion at each joint is broken down into its more fundamental components, called degrees of freedom. Players are faced with the challenge of controlling the several degrees of freedom to recreate lifelike motions such as crawling, walking, jumping, and even dancing. These challenges are similar to the ones faced by roboticists trying to develop lifelike, robust and balanced motions for legged robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprenger discusses the unique ways different age groups and genders interact with the software. Through incorporating feedback from the students, Sprenger adds new activities and challenges to keep students engaged and challenged, improving their understanding of robot control.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Evolutionary Approaches for Flying Robots</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2016/05/01/Evolutionary-approaches-for-flying-robots/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2016/05/01/Evolutionary-approaches-for-flying-robots</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Episode #207: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/robots-evolutionary-approaches-for-flying-robots/&quot;&gt;Evolutionary Approaches for Flying Robots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/guido-de-coon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guido De Croon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/289965233&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I interview Guido De Croon about Evolutionary Robotics and its use to design behaviors for flying robots. We discuss a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?arnumber=7412843&amp;amp;filter%3DAND%28p_IS_Number%3A7412841%29&quot;&gt;recent paper&lt;/a&gt; by Kirk Schepe et al., in which the DelFly UAV robot learns to fly through an open window when trapped inside a room thanks to a controller optimized using a Genetic Algorithm. The controller is programmed using a Behavior Tree Framework, which is more intuitive and adaptable than the traditional Neural Network framework. This helps the user to manually adapt the controller to handle the differences between the simulation and the real world. Guido then discusses the challenges and benefits of using Evolutionary Robotics to learn robot behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Driven by care needs, will it be the booming senior population that spurs wider acceptance of robots?</title>
   <link href="https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2014/10/19/elderly-acceptance-of-robotics/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://abatedemey.github.io/personal_website/2014/10/19/elderly-acceptance-of-robotics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-40013&quot; alt=&quot;Silhouettes wheelchair and crowds people&quot; src=&quot;https://robohub.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/bigstock-Silhouettes-wheelchair-and-cro-63621802.jpg&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;636&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheffield.ac.uk/psychology/staff/academic/tony-prescott&quot;&gt;Tony Prescott&lt;/a&gt;, Professor of Cognitive Neuroscience and Director of the Sheffield Center of Robotics believes that [tweetquote]the medical industry could be at the forefront of changing the public perception of robotics. Why?[/tweetquote] Because this is an industry that already understands how paramount it is, when dealing with the elderly, disabled and ill, to provide a service that is helpful, friendly and nonthreatening.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking this week at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.re-work.co/workshops/future-of-robotics&quot;&gt;RE.WORK&lt;/a&gt; – an event that explores the challenges of commercializing robotics – Prescott recalled the fear people had in the 90s about the coming of the Internet. Similarly, he said, reporters often ask him: “When will robots take over the world?” The question has perhaps become a cliché among roboticists, but in his presentation (aptly titled “Robots that know themselves will make better carers”) Prescott suggested that much can be learned from neuroscience and psychology to improve the safety and effectiveness – and by extension the public perception – of human-robot interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sprfocus10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;sprfocusl&quot; href=&quot;/tag/robots-for-eldercare/&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aging population is increasing rapidly, and there are not enough caregivers to satisfy the growing demand. It is projected that by 2060, there will be one dependent person for every working person in the EU. Per visit, caretakers have limited time in which to interact the elderly people in their care, and time must be divided between aiding with personal hygiene tasks, ordering/preparing food, and one-on-one conversation time. As such, seniors must often make difficult decisions to prioritize the services they wish to receive from caregivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prescott said that personal robots could aid seniors with time consuming household tasks such as making a pot of tea, reaching for the salt, opening a jar, or microwaving food – tasks that could be frustrating if you have to wait around for help. Personal hygiene tasks such as showering or using the toilet can create an embarrassing dynamic between the elderly and the caretaker, and so also make ideal tasks for robot care assistants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prescott points out that the role of a robot should be to assist the senior and the caregiver, not to take over.  “Robots can help caregivers, not by replacing them, (but by working with them).”  With the aid of personal robots, caretakers could spend more time engaging in one-on-one conversation with the elderly, providing valuable social interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet we cannot stop people from getting personally attached to the items they own, Prescott explains. People like to glue fur to their Roombas to make them feel more like pets, and robot companions like the Paro have been shown to induce relaxation, reduce stress, and stimulate communication between patients and caregivers. The important distinction to remember, suggested Prescott, is that the companionship people feel toward their robots is more in line with how they feel toward their pets, and the need for human companionship will always remain critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we can learn to design robots that can work as part of a care team, public perception of robots is sure to change.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
